var quiz = [{"answers": ["Asteroid impacts", "Trees", "Early mammals", "Cyanobacteria"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "_____________ changed the composition of the atmosphere so that there was more oxygen and less CO   2"}, {"answers": ["photosynthesis", "the carbon cycle", "the carbon dioxide cycle", "the greenhouse effect"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The movement of carbon between the atmosphere, oceans, plants, animals, and soil is known as _______."}, {"answers": ["United States", "Mexico", "India", "China"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "At the time the Kyoto Protocol was proposed, which nation was the largest producer of carbon emissions in the world?"}, {"answers": ["stayed the same", "decreased", "had no relationship to CO2 concentration.", "increased"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Proxy data covering the past 800,000 years shows that as CO2 levels have increased on Earth, temperatures have:"}, {"answers": ["direct and proxy measurements of temperature.", "direct measurements of carbon dioxide.", "direct measurements of ice cores.", "direct measurements of sea level."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The data that were used to make the Keeling curve come from"}, {"answers": ["Earth\u2019s forests", "Earth\u2019s oceans", "Earth\u2019s crust", "Earth\u2019s living organisms"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Most of Earth\u2019s carbon is locked up in what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "A developing country is likely to emit more carbon dioxide per capita than a developed country."}, {"answers": ["ethics", "politics", "religion", "economy"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The link to ___________ is the primary reason that efforts to reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions have not been as successful as they could have been."}, {"answers": ["carbon offset programs", "command-and-control", "institutionalized agreements such as Montreal Protocol", "building collective relationships between parties involved"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "A market environmentalist would most likely support _______ as a solution to address climate change?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The greenhouse effect is necessary for life on Earth as we know it."}, {"answers": ["The ocean has become more acidic over the last century.", "Global sea level has risen about 8 inches over the last century.", "Temperatures have increased about 6 \u00b0F over the last century.", "Nearly all mountain glaciers have retreated or disappeared in the last century."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Many scientists assert that the Earth is changing as a result of rising atmospheric CO2 concentrations. Which of the following statements is NOT some of the evidence given?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Global warming is the term used to describe all forms of long-term climate fluctuations."}, {"answers": ["Ecocentric", "Incentive-based", "Ethics-based", "Command-and-control"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Environmental regulation in the U.S. has traditionally relied on what type of policies?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The Kyoto Protocol sets mandatory, legally-binding emission reduction targets for    all parties subject to it."}, {"answers": ["Ice Cores", "Ozone monitoring", "Ancient coral reefs", "Tree rings"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following\u00a0 are considered proxy records that have been used to estimate Earth\u2019s temperatures for thousands of years prior to direct measurement, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["6 \u00b0F", "61 \u00b0F", "50 \u00b0F", "20 \u00b0F"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Without the greenhouse effect, the average temperature on Earth would be how much colder than present?"}, {"answers": ["Fall", "Spring", "Summer", "Winter"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "CO   2 levels fluctuate throughout the year, with the seasons. During which season would we expect to see the lowest levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide in the Northern Hemisphere?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Two billion years ago Earth\u2019s atmosphere had more carbon dioxide than oxygen in it."}, {"answers": ["Countries that benefit from carbon emission reductions without experiencing the costs are free-riders.", "Only a few countries would benefit from the reduction of greenhouse gases.", "Negative impacts are not always felt in the same place that carbon is emitted.", "Only countries that make reductions in carbon emissions would suffer."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true concerning global emissions of carbon dioxide?"}, {"answers": ["Methane", "Nitrogen", "HCFCs", "Carbon dioxide"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following are greenhouse gases, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Montreal Protocol", "Kyoto Protocol", "Carbon Offset Referendum", "US Conference of Mayors\u2019 Climate Protection Agreement"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The _______ was signed in 2005 as one example of a local response to the global problem of climate change."}, {"answers": ["Flexibility", "Equality", "Enforceability", "Accountability"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "What is cited as one of the benefits of the Kyoto Protocol that made it easier for many countries to sign on?"}, {"answers": ["0.5", "10", "1", "5"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "According to records, CO   2 levels have been increasing about ___% per year since 1958?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The Keeling curve shows an overall increasing trend in the concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere."}, {"answers": ["These countries emit less CO2 per capita than developing countries.", "These countries generally have stable or declining populations.", "These countries include the \u201cdeveloped\u201d countries of the world.", "These countries emitted the most CO2 in order to become developed."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true concerning Annex 1 countries in the Kyoto Protocol?"}, {"answers": ["It is an example of the first contradiction in capitalism.", "The sites of emissions and the sites of impacts are usually different.", "Decreasing emissions could make a firm less competitive.", "Wealthy people produce the most carbon, and are usually the least affected by it."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are reasons why political economists prefer non-market regulatory solutions, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Paying a factory owner to reduce carbon emissions would be an example of utilizing the Coase theorem."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The greenhouse effect is a natural process."}, {"answers": ["market mechanisms", "incentives", "governmental monitoring", "regulation standards"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "A market environmentalist would argue that given the right ________ companies would innovate and reduce their emissions without need for command-and-control policies."}, {"answers": ["Montreal Protocol", "Copenhagen Treaty", "US Conference of Mayors\u2019 Climate Protection Agreement", "Kyoto Protocol"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The _______ was enacted in order to specifically reduce the concentration of CFCs in the atmosphere."}]

quizCollection['9'] = quiz
